JOHN GALINDEZ

T-Shaped Frontend Engineer • Pragmatic • Product-Driven Thinker

Madrid • contact@johndez.net • +34 603-785-663

linkedin/in/jgalindez • github/johndezr

SUMMARY

Senior Frontend Engineer with +8 years of experience designing and building interactive web applications. I am the person in the middle of frontend architecture, UX/UI, and AI-driven products. I consider myself a team player, participant of clean, scalable systems and collaborative problem-solving.

SKILLS

AI/ML: OpenAI API, Pinecone Vector DDBB, Replica, AI SDK, TensorFlow & ML5.

Infra/Testing: Nginx, Digital Ocean, Jenkins, Github CI/CD, Vitest, Testing Library, Cypress.

Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Python.

Frameworks/Libraries: Vue.js, React, Astro, Next, Nuxt, Tanstack Query. **Architecture:** MVC/MVVM, Clean/Hexagonal Arquitecture, Microfrontends.

Principles: TDD, SOLID, DDD.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Al Engineer, Freelance, Remote

Nov 2024 - Present

• Integrated AI/ML capabilities into front-end applications, collaborating with AI engineers and designers to optimize interfaces, automate processes, and reduce operational costs with: n8n, MCP servers, Replica, LangChain, Pinecone, ML5.

Software Engineer - ioBuilders, Remote

Jun 2023 - Oct 2024

 Worked for the company's main client in New Zealand (Veve), developing important features for different web and mobile applications with: React Native, Next.js, Typescript, React Testing, Css-in-JS.

Frontend Lead - Flexicar, Remote

Dec 2021 - May 2023

• Deployment and development to production of the company's main website with hundreds of thousands of users and bookings per month. I worked closely with other areas of the company to ensure the portal was aligned with strategic objectives, using: Next.js, Nest,js, TailwindCSS, Jenkins.

Software Engineer (CTO) - Greyhounders, Madrid

Feb 2020 - Nov 2021

 Built the SSR e-commerce from scratch with Nuxt.js, helping the founding team to make businesstechnology decisions, making a big impact on the optical industry through AR.

Frontend Lead - Financial Services of Carrefour, Madrid

Jan 2019 - Dec 2020

• Technical and architectural leader in the construction of a component catalog that allowed +10 applications in production with hundreds of recurring users to embed it, thus achieving an effective visualization in each one of them. Tech Stack: Vue.js Typescript, Storyblok, Web Components.

Software Engineer - Sipay Plus, Madrid

Nov 2016 - Dec 2018

• Main front-end dev in the construction of the administrative website for the visualisation of thousands of dynamic banking operations from design to production, using Vue.js HTML5, Sass, Phyton.

EDUCATION

Computer Science - UCAB

Jan 2013 - Jun 2016

• Programming mentor during my first year of my career.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Soft Skills: Team player, Attention to detail, Charismatic, Empathy, Communication is key.
- Languages: Spanish (Native), English (Fluent).
- · Experience with Agile development methodologies.
- A pragmatic, right-tool-for-the-job mentality.